Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Ford collateral literature, 1939-2007 and undated RL.11679
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Competitive Brands, 1948-2004 and undated; 4
  - Buick, 1973, 2004; 2 folders (Box COM8)
  - Bus bodies--Americoach, 1950s (Box COM1)
  - Bus bodies--Blue Bird, 1961-1962 (Box COM1)
  - Bus bodies--Carpenter, 1954-1962 (Box COM1)
  - Bus bodies--Highliner (Coach and Equipment Sales Corporation), 1969-1972 (Box COM1)
  - Bus bodies--Oneida, 1961 (Box COM1)
  - Bus bodies--Superior, 1961 (Box OV2)
  - Bus bodies--Thomas, 1963 (Box COM1)
  - Bus bodies--Ward, 1961 (Box COM1)
  - Bus bodies--Wayne, 1958 (Box COM1)
  - Cadillac, 1993-2000 (Box COM1)
  - Cadillac, 1990-1998 (Box COM8)
  - Chevrolet, 1954-1981; 21 folders (Box COM1)
  - Chevrolet, 1962-1971; 4 folders (Box COM8)
  - Chevrolet, 1965-1966 (Box OV2)
  - Chevrolet, 1972-1987; 6 folders (Box COM9)
  - Chevrolet, 1982-2000; 9 folders (Box COM2)
  - Chevrolet--Chevy Camper magazine, 1972 (Box COM2)
  - Chevrolet--Corvette 40th anniversary book, 1993 (Box COM9)
  - Chevrolet--Direct mail, 1963-1972 (Box COM9)
  - Chevrolet--Direct mail, 1963-1976; 10 folders (Box COM2)
  - Chevrolet--Engineering Features of Chevrolet Trucks, 1966 (Box COM2)
  - Chevrolet--Payload magazine, 1974-1975 (Box COM2)
  - Chevrolet--S-10 pickup, 2000 (Box COM9)
  - Chrysler, 1964-1965 (Box OV2)
  - Chrysler, 1984-1997; 3 folders (Box COM2)
  - Chrysler Canada, 1983 (Box COM2)
  - Chrysler direct mail, 1964-1965 (Box COM10)
  - Chrysler Imperial, 1974 (Box OV2)
  - Chrysler/Imperial/Plymouth direct mail, 1964-1965 (Box COM2)
  - Chrysler-Plymouth minivans, 1998 (Box COM10)
  - Competitive comparisons, 1952-1971; 7 folders (Box COM2)
  - Dodge, 1962-1966; 5 folders (Box COM2)
  - Dodge, 1967-1999; 21 folders (Box COM3)
  - Dodge, 1968-1986; 5 folders (Box COM10)
  - Dodge, 1987; 2 folders (Box COM11)
  - Dodge Body Builder's Book, 1966, 1970 (Box COM11)
  - Dodge Viper, 1996 (Box COM11)
  - Dodge direct mail, 1962-1976; 4 folders (Box COM3)
  - Dodge truck operator's manual, 1963 (Box COM3)
  - Engine comparisons, 1957-1964; 2 folders (Box COM3)
  - Fact Favor Ford (comparisons), 1980 (Box COM3)
  - Federal, 1951-1953 (Box COM3)
  - Fiber Glass Bodies, 1960-1969 (Box COM3)
  - Ford-Chevrolet comparisons, 1964 (Box COM3)
  - Ford Summary Performance Test Report, 1976 (Box COM3)
    Comparisons between Ford Pinto, Datsun B-210, Toyota Corolla, Chevrolet Chevette
  - Ford v. Chevy Truck Price Comparison Guides, 1966-1967 (Box COM3)
  - General Motors--American Youth magazine, 1964 (Box COM3)
  - General Motors--Electric Vehicle project, approximately 1990 (Box COM3)
  - Geo, 1993 (Box COM3)
  - GMC, 1962-1978; 18 folders (Box COM3)
  - GMC, 1963-1984; 5 folders (Box COM12)
  - GMC, 1964-1965 (Box OV2)
  - GMC, 1979-1987; 11 folders (Box COM4)
  - GMC--Direct mail, 1963-1974; 3 folders (Box COM4)
  - Hind, 1973 (Box COM4)
  - Honda comparisons, 1994 (Box COM4)
  - Hummer, 1994-1995 (Box COM4)
  - Infiniti, 2000 (Box COM4)
  - International Harvester, 1959-1983; 15 folders (Box COM4)
  - International Harvester, 1968-1970 (Box COM12)
  - Isuzu, 1982-1987 (Box COM4)
  - Jaguar, 1995-1997 (Box COM12)
  - Jaguar, 1999 (Box COM4)
  - Kenworth, 1965-1976 (Box COM4)
  - Land Rover, 1970 (Box COM4)
  - Lexus, 1994-1997 (Box COM12)
  - Lexus, 1994-2000 (Box COM4)
  - Lincoln-Mercury, 1964-1993; 2 folders (Box COM12)
  - Lincoln-Mercury, 1977-2000; 5 folders (Box COM4)
  - Lincoln-Mercury (includes direct mail), 1994-1998; 3 folders (Box COM13)
  - Lincoln-Mercury (includes direct mail), 1995-1998 (Box OV2)
  - Lincoln-Mercury, 1997-2001; 2 folders (Box COM5)
  - Lincoln-Mercury, 1999-2001; 2 folders (Box COM14)
  - Lincoln-Mercury--Accessories catalogs, 1977-1992; 3 folders (Box COM5)
  - Lincoln-Mercury--Continental magazine, 1965-1967 (Box COM5)
  - Lincoln-Mercury--Direct mail, 1964-1973; 2 folders (Box COM5)
  - Mack, 1959-1978 (Box COM5)
  - Mack, 1964 (Box COM14)
  - Mazda, 1982 (Box COM14)
  - Mazda, 1982-1999; 6 folders (Box COM5)
  - Mazda (English and Japanese), 1989 (Box COM5)
  - Medium truck comparisons, 1964 (Box COM5)
  - Mercedes-Benz, 1960-1997 (Box COM5)
  - Mercury, 1980-1995; 2 folders (Box COM14)
  - Mercury, 1997-1998; 2 folders (Box COM15)
  - Mini Cooper, 2004 (Box COM5)
  - Miscellaneous print advertisements, 1977-1978 (Box COM5)
  - Mitsubishi, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box COM15)
  - Mitsubishi, 1984-1997; 4 folders (Box COM5)
  - Nissan/Datsun, 1961-1993; 5 folders (Box COM5)
  - Nissan/Datsun, 1980-1984; 5 folders (Box COM15)
  - Nissan/Datsun, 1985-1987; 3 folders (Box COM16)
  - Nissan/Datsun--Cima (Japanese), 1993 (Box OV2)
  - Oldsmobile, 1965-1998 (Box COM5)
  - Oldsmobile, 1997 (Box COM16)
  - Oshkosh, 1958-1976 (Box COM5)
  - Page and Page, 1960 (Box COM5)
  - Peterbilt, 1965-1976; 2 folders (Box COM5)
  - Plymouth, 1964-1996; 5 folders (Box COM5)
  - Plymouth, 1969-1987 (Box COM16)
  - Pontiac, 1999-2001 (Box COM5)
  - Price lists--Jeep, Chevrolet, Dodge, Plymouth, 1978-1979; 3 folders (Box COM5)
  - Ranchero v. El Camino, 1970 (Box COM5)
  - Recreational vehicles, 1965-1968 (Box COM5)
  - Rectrans/Discoverer 27, 1971 (Box COM5)
  - Reference Guides to Competitive Trucks, 1958-1969, 1984; 2 folders (Box COM6)
  - Reference Guides to Mack, Diamond Reo, White trucks, 1968 (Box COM6)
  - Renault vans, 1960 (Box COM6)
  - Reo trucks, 1960-1965 (Box COM6)
  - Rootes/Karrier trucks (U.K.), 1948 (Box COM6)
  - Rosenbauer (airplane crash tender; text in English and German), 1992 (Box COM6)
  - Roustabout/Trivan, 1963 (Box COM6)
  - Since You Bought Your Chevrolet--, 1963 (Box COM6)
  - Subaru, 1983-1990; 3 folders (Box COM6)
  - Subaru (English and Japanese), 1984-1989; 2 folders (Box COM16)
  - T.L. Smith--Smith-Mobile, 1966 (Box COM6)
  - Toyota, 1971-1983; 4 folders (Box COM17)
  - Toyota, 1971-1987; 5 folders (Box COM6)
  - Toyota, 1984-1994; 4 folders (Box COM18)
  - Troyler, 1960 (Box COM6)
  - Truck and van comparisons, 1967-1969 (Box COM6)
  - U.S. Steel, 1967 (Box COM6)
  - Utilimaster, 1981 (Box COM6)
  - Volkswagen direct mail, 1964-1976 (Box COM6)
  - Volvo, Freightliner, 1960-1980 (Box COM7)
  - White, 1959-1982; 3 folders (Box COM7)
  - White--Alley Cat (city service truck), 1969-1971 (Box COM7)
  - White--Engines, 1957-1966 (Box COM7)
  - White--Freightliner, 1961-1983 (Box COM7)
  - White--Specifications, 1964 (Box COM7)
  - Yamaha (snowmobiles), undated (Box COM7)
- International Materials, 1959-2002 and undated; 5
  - Argentina (Spanish), 1996-1998 (Box INT1)
  - Australia, 1996-2001; 4 folders (Box INT1)
  - Australia, 1995-1999 (Box INT2)
  - Australia--History of the Ford Falcon 1960-1994 (Box INT1)
  - Austria (German), 1969 (Box INT2)
  - Canada, 2000 (Box INT1)
  - Canada--Truck owner report, 1964 (Box INT1)
  - China (Chinese), 1995 (Box INT1)
  - China (Chinese), 1995 (Box INT2)
  - Europe--Czech, 1998 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--Danish, 1998 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--English, 1995-2000 and undated; 4 folders (Box INT1)
  - Europe--Flemish (Belgium), 1996-1997 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--French, 1997-1999 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--Hungarian, 1997 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--Italian, 1996-1997 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--Multi-lingual, 2000-2001 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--Norwegian, 1997 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--Russian, 1998 (Box INT1)
  - Europe--Product Training Kits, 1997 (Box INT1)
  - Germany/Austria (German), 1996-2001 (Box INT1)
  - Germany/Austria--Callaway Cars (GT versions of Chevrolet Corvette), undated (Box INT1)
  - Great Britain, 1992-2002; 5 folders (Box INT1)
  - Great Britain--How the Diesel Engine Works and Servicing the Diesel Fuel System, 1960 (Box INT1)
  - Great Britain--Renault commercial vehicle data, 1959 (Box INT1)
  - Great Britain--Thecar2wait4 direct mail, 2000 (Box INT2)
  - Great Britain--Trucks, 1969-1976 (Box INT1)
  - Ireland, 2001-2002 (Box INT1)
  - Japan (Japanese), 1994 (Box INT2)
  - Middle East (Arabic), 1995-1999; 2 folders (Box INT1)
  - Middle East (Arabic), 1990 (Box INT2)
  - Middle East (Arabic)--Lincoln-Mercury, 1991-1996; 2 folders (Box INT1)
  - Middle East (Arabic)--Lincoln-Mercury, 1990-1995 (Box INT2)
  - Netherlands (Dutch), 1996-2001 (Box INT1)
  - Peru (Spanish), undated (Box INT1)
  - Portugal (Portuguese), 1997-1999 (Box INT1)
  - Switzerland (Italian), 1996 (Box INT1)
- Technical Literature, 1939-1983 and undated; 6
  - 168 Shop Kink Ideas from Fleet Owner, 1959 (Box TEC1)
  - Automatic Transmission Diagnosis, 1970 (Box TEC1)
  - Automobile Facts and Figures, 1939-1961; 4 folders (Box TEC1)
  - Automotive Service Digest--Crankcase Ventilation, 1956 (Box TEC1)
  - Bigger Choice in the Big Fords, 1964 (Box TEC1)
  - Bronco Training Handbook, 1966 (Box TEC1)
  - Courier Shop Manual, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box TEC1)
  - Courier technical press information, 1972 (Box TEC1)
  - Crown Steel Products--Crew Cabs for Ford Trucks, 1965 (Box TEC1)
  - Diesel Engines, 1967-1968 (Box TEC1)
  - Driveline Selection and Performance Guide, 1968 (Box TEC1)
  - Driver's Handbook and Digest of ICC Driver Regulations (Private Truck Council), 1957 (Box TEC1)
  - Eaton axles, 1968-1970; 2 folders (Box TEC1)
  - Eaton--Primer on Tandem/Dual-Axle Drive Trucks, 1955 (Box TEC1)
  - Engine Equipment Installation Manual, 1960-1961; 2 folders (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Axle, Engine and Transmission Guide, 1964, 1968; 2 folders (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Mechanic--Four-Barrel Carburetor Service Tips, 1957 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Mechanic--Servicing Ford Carburetors, 1955 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Mechanic--Servicing the Single-Barrel Carburetor, 1956 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Mechanic--Transmatic Operation and Adjustments, 1957 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Mechanic--Truck Service Features, 1956 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Report--Alternative Fuels, 1991 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Service Manager--8 and 10-Speed Fuller Transmission Service, 1961 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Service Technician--1960 Truck Carburetor Service (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Service Technician--1961 Econoline Body Service (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Service Technician--8 and 10-Speed Fuller Transmission Service, 1961 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Service Technician--Servicing the 1961 Econoline Chassis (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Service Technician--Servicing the 262 Ford Truck Engine, 1961 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Transmatic, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Truck Detailed Component Descriptions, 1972 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Truck Gradeability, 1970 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Truck Operation Analysis Forms, 1961 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford Truck shop manuals, 1958-1962 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford/Caterpillar vs. Cummins Diesel Engine Analysis, 1968 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford/Caterpillar vs. International Harvester Diesel Engine Analysis, 1968 (Box TEC1)
  - Ford-Aire suspension shop manual, 1958 (Box TEC1)
  - Fordomatic shop manual, 1956 (Box TEC1)
  - Gas and diesel engine ratings, 1966 (Box TEC1)
  - General Motors Stirling Engine, 1969 (Box TEC1)
  - Glass regulator and sash channel list for 1937-1939 cars and trucks, 1949 (Box TEC1)
  - Hildy's Blue Book (special equipment for Ford Trucks), 1949-1959 (Box TEC1)
  - Hildy's Blue Book (special equipment for Ford Trucks), 1959-1983 (Box TEC2)
  - How the Fuel System Operates, 1966 (Box TEC2)
  - Industrial engines, 1959-1969 (Box TEC2)
  - Kysor Heating Company brochure, undated (Box TEC2)
  - Louisville Heavy Truck Modification Center, 1968 (Box TEC2)
  - Memco Mobile Cranes, 1955 (Box TEC2)
  - Motor Truck Facts, 1953-1973; 3 folders (Box TEC2)
  - Mustang comparisons, 1979 (Box TEC2)
  - Passsenger Car Data, 1949-1951; 3 folders (Box TEC2)
  - Pre-Delivery Service Sequence Guide, 1965 (Box TEC3)
  - Reference Manual--Cars and Trucks, 1942 (Box TEC3)
  - Roadranger Transmission Service Manual, 1957 (Box TEC3)
  - Rockwell axles, 1960-1969; 2 folders (Box TEC3)
  - Rockwell--Standard axles for Ford Trucks, 1967 (Box TEC3)
  - Safety--Design Factors in Automotive Safety (A.L. Haynes), 1955 (Box TEC3)
  - Safety--Human and Environmental Factors in Automobile Safety (Ross McFarland), 1955 (Box TEC3)
  - Safety--Motor Vehicle and Highway Safety Acts of 1966 (Box TEC3)
  - Safety--Motor Vehicle Safety Defect Recall Campaigns (U.S. Department of Transportation), 1967 (Box TEC3)
  - Safety--Motor Vehicular Safety Standards Guide (Truck Body and Equipment Association), 1968 (Box TEC3)
  - Safety--Safety Equipment Required and Permitted, 1953 (Box TEC3)
  - Safety--Stewart-Warner Safety Panels, 1955 (Box TEC3)
  - Safety--Traffic safety features in cars, 1955-1966 (Box TEC3)
  - Service Specifications for Trucks, 1966 (Box TEC3)
  - Shop Talk newsletter, 1958 (Box TEC3)
  - Shop Talk newsletter--1960 preview, 1959 (Box TEC3)
  - Shop Tips from Ford, 1966; 2 folders (Box TEC3)
  - Transistorized Ignition, 1964 (Box TEC3)
  - Truck cab dimension comparison, 1967 (Box TEC4)
  - Truck shop manual supplement, 1975 (Box TEC4)
  - Twin-I Beam front suspension, 1963-1971 (Box TEC4)
  - Twin-I Beam SAE report, 1965 (Box TEC4)
  - V-8 engine power curve comparisons, 1958 (Box TEC4)
  - V-Series diesel application slide rule, 1968 (Box TEC4)
  - Vehicle NVH (Noise, Vibration, Harshness) (R.W. Alexander), 1966 (Box TEC4)
  - Westran/Austin Wedge-Lok fifth wheel, 1965-1969 (Box TEC4)